<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackerrank on programmerCave</title>
    <link>https://programmercave.com/tags/Hackerrank/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackerrank on programmerCave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://programmercave.com/tags/Hackerrank/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Left Rotation - HackerRank | C&#43;&#43; Implementation</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Left-Rotation-HackerRank-Challenge-Cpp-Implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Left-Rotation-HackerRank-Challenge-Cpp-Implementation/</guid>
      <description>A left rotation operation on an array of size n shifts each of the array&amp;rsquo;s elements 1 unit to the left. For example, if 2 left rotations are performed on array [1, 2, 3, 4, 5], then the array would become [3, 4, 5, 1, 2].&#xA;Given an array of n integers and a number, d, perform d left rotations on the array. Then print the updated array as a single line of space-separated integers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repeated String - HackerRank | C&#43;&#43; Implementation</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Repeated-String-HackerRank-Challenge-Cpp-Implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Repeated-String-HackerRank-Challenge-Cpp-Implementation/</guid>
      <description>Lilah has a string, s, of lowercase English letters that she repeated infinitely many times.&#xA;Given an integer, n, find and print the number of letter a&amp;rsquo;s in the first n letters of Lilah&amp;rsquo;s infinite string.&#xA;For example, if the string s = ‘abcac’ and n = 10, the substring we consider is , abcacabcac the first 10 characters of her infinite string. There are 4 occurrences of a in the substring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picking Numbers - HackerRank | C&#43;&#43; Implementation</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Picking-Numbers-HackerRank-Challenge-Cpp-Implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Picking-Numbers-HackerRank-Challenge-Cpp-Implementation/</guid>
      <description>Given an array of integers, find and print the maximum number of integers you can select from the array such that the absolute difference between any two of the chosen integers is less than or equal to 1.&#xA;For example, if your array is a = [1, 1, 2, 2, 4, 4, 5, 5, 5], you can create two subarrays meeting the criterion: [1, 1, 2, 2] and [4, 4, 5, 5, 5].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Library Fine | HackerRank</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Library-Fine--HackerRank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Library-Fine--HackerRank/</guid>
      <description>This is an easy hackerrank challenge which will help you to become good at competitive programming. There are various competitive programming websites like CodeChef, HackerEarth, Codeforces where you can practice coding.&#xA;Your local library needs your help! Given the expected and actual return dates for a library book, create a program that calculates the fine (if any). The fee structure is as follows:&#xA;• If the book is returned on or before the expected return date, no fine will be charged (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sherlock and Squares | HackerRank</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Sherlock-and-Squares--HackerRank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Sherlock-and-Squares--HackerRank/</guid>
      <description>This is an easy hackerrank challenge which will help you to become good at competitive programming. There are various competitive programming websites like CodeChef, HackerEarth, Codeforces where you can practice coding.&#xA;Watson likes to challenge Sherlock&amp;rsquo;s math ability. He will provide a starting and ending value describing a range of integers. Sherlock must determine the number of square integers within that range, inclusive of the endpoints.&#xA;Note: A square integer is an integer which is the square of an integer, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circular Array Rotation | HackerRank</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Circular-Array-Rotation--HackerRank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Circular-Array-Rotation--HackerRank/</guid>
      <description>This is an easy hackerrank challenge which will help you to become good at competitive programming. There are various competitive programming websites like CodeChef, HackerEarth, Codeforces where you can practice coding.&#xA;John Watson knows of an operation called a right circular rotation on an array of integers. One rotation operation moves the last array element to the first position and shifts all remaining elements right one. To test Sherlock&amp;rsquo;s abilities, Watson provides Sherlock with an array of integers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Book | HackerRank</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Drawing-Book--HackerRank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Drawing-Book--HackerRank/</guid>
      <description>This is an easy hackerrank challenge which will help you to become good at competitive programming. There are various competitive programming websites like CodeChef, HackerEarth, Codeforces where you can practice coding.&#xA;Brie’s Drawing teacher asks her class to open their books to a page number. Brie can either start turning pages from the front of the book or from the back of the book. She always turns pages one at a time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migratory Birds - HackerRank Challenge | C&#43;&#43; Implementation</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Migratory-Birds-HackerRank-Challenge-C-Implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Migratory-Birds-HackerRank-Challenge-C-Implementation/</guid>
      <description>You have been asked to help study the population of birds migrating across the continent. Each type of bird you are interested in will be identified by an integer value. Each time a particular kind of bird is spotted, its id number will be added to your array of sightings. You would like to be able to find out which type of bird is most common given a list of sightings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Between Two Sets - HackerRank Challenge | C&#43;&#43; Implementation</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Between-Two-Sets-HackerRank-Challenge-C-Implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Between-Two-Sets-HackerRank-Challenge-C-Implementation/</guid>
      <description>You will be given two arrays of integers and asked to determine all integers that satisfy the following two conditions:&#xA;The elements of the first array are all factors of the integer being considered The integer being considered is a factor of all elements of the second array These numbers are referred to as being between the two arrays. You must determine how many such numbers exist.&#xA;For example, given the arrays a =[2, 6] and b = [24, 36], there are two numbers between them: 6 and 12.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kangaroo HackerRank Challenge | C&#43;&#43; Implementation</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Kangaroo-HackerRank-Challenge-C-Implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Kangaroo-HackerRank-Challenge-C-Implementation/</guid>
      <description>You are choreographing a circus show with various animals. For one act, you are given two kangaroos o a number line ready to jump in the positive direction (i.e, toward positive infinity).&#xA;• The first kangaroo starts at location x1 and moves at a rate of v1 meters per jump. • The second kangaroo starts at location x2 and moves at a rate of v2 meters per jump.&#xA;You have to figure out a way to get both kangaroos at the same location at the same time as part of the show.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
