<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview-Questions on programmerCave</title>
    <link>https://programmercave.com/tags/Interview-Questions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview-Questions on programmerCave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://programmercave.com/tags/Interview-Questions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: Explain CAP Theorem</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Explain-CAP-Theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Explain-CAP-Theorem/</guid>
      <description>1. What is the CAP Theorem? The CAP Theorem states that a distributed system can only guarantee two out of three properties at the same time:
 Consistency (C): All users see the same data simultaneously. Availability (A): The system always responds to requests (even with stale data). Partition Tolerance (P): The system works even if parts of it lose communication.  Key Insight: Network partitions (e.g., server crashes, dropped messages) are unavoidable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: What is the difference between SQL and NoSQL Databases?</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-What-is-the-difference-between-SQL-and-NoSQL-Databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-What-is-the-difference-between-SQL-and-NoSQL-Databases/</guid>
      <description>SQL vs NoSQL: The Ultimate Guide for Software Engineering Interviews Understanding the differences between SQL and NoSQL databases is a common requirement for technical interviews. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a new grad or a seasoned engineer, interviewers often test your ability to choose the right database for specific use cases. Let’s break down these differences to help you prepare effectively.
Why SQL vs NoSQL Matters in Interviews Interviewers assess your understanding of database fundamentals to evaluate your system design skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: What is the difference between MySQL and PostgreSQL?</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-What-is-the-difference-between-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-What-is-the-difference-between-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL/</guid>
      <description>Database Type  MySQL: A purely relational database management system known for its simplicity and speed, making it suitable for web applications and read-heavy workloads. PostgreSQL: An object-relational database management system (ORDBMS) that supports advanced features like table inheritance and custom data types, making it versatile for complex applications.  Data Integrity and Concurrency  PostgreSQL: Strongly emphasizes data integrity with Multi-Version Concurrency Control (MVCC), allowing multiple transactions without locking the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: Explain Slices in Golang</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Explain-Slices-in-Golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Explain-Slices-in-Golang/</guid>
      <description>Slices in Go are essential for handling collections of data flexibly and efficiently. This guide will help you grasp the core concepts of slices, ensuring you are well-prepared for your upcoming Golang interview.
What Are Slices? Slices are built on top of arrays and offer a dynamic way to manage sequences of elements. They consist of three main components:
 Pointer: Points to the first element of the underlying array. Length: Indicates the number of elements in the slice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: How Does Internally Indexing Work in Databases?</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-How-Does-Internally-Indexing-Work-in-Databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-How-Does-Internally-Indexing-Work-in-Databases/</guid>
      <description>Definition of Indexing  Indexing is a technique used to improve the speed of data retrieval in databases by creating a separate data structure that maps search keys to their corresponding data locations.  Internal Structures   B-Tree Structure:
 The most common structure for indexes, allowing sorted data and efficient searching, insertion, and deletion.  B-Tree Diagram  [Root] / \ / \ [A] [B] / \ / \ [C] [D] [E] [F]   Leaf Nodes: Store actual data pointers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: What is Database Sharding?</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-What-is-Database-Sharding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-What-is-Database-Sharding/</guid>
      <description>Key Concepts of Database Sharding Definition:
 Database sharding is the process of partitioning a large database into smaller, manageable pieces called shards. Each shard operates independently and contains a subset of the total data, allowing for parallel processing and improved query performance.  Purpose:
 The main objective of sharding is to effectively manage large datasets. As applications grow, a single database instance may struggle with increased data volume and user demand, resulting in slower response times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: Why Go is One of the Fastest Programming Languages?</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Why-Go-is-One-of-the-Fastest-Programming-Languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Why-Go-is-One-of-the-Fastest-Programming-Languages/</guid>
      <description>Explore the reasons why Go (Golang) is one of the fastest programming languages available today. This blog delves into key features that contribute to Go&amp;rsquo;s performance, including its compiled nature, efficient concurrency model with goroutines, optimized garbage collection, and simplicity in code design. Ideal for developers preparing for Golang interviews, this guide offers essential insights into how Go leverages modern hardware and achieves rapid compile times, making it a top choice for high-performance applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: Build a Simple URL Shortener in Go</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Build-a-Simple-URL-Shortener-in-Go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Interview-Question-Build-a-Simple-URL-Shortener-in-Go/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we will build a simple URL shortener in Go. This will demonstrate how to generate short codes for long URLs, store them in memory, and retrieve the original URL from the short code. We will also ensure thread-safety for concurrent access to the in-memory store using sync.Mutex.
This question was asked to me by Radisys for the role of Golang Developer.
 Step 1: Data Structure for Storing URLs First, we need a place to store the URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Question: Thread-Safe Implementation of Map in Go</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Thread-Safe-Implementation-of-Map-in-Go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Thread-Safe-Implementation-of-Map-in-Go/</guid>
      <description>This blog demonstrates two approaches to implement a thread-safe map in Go: using sync.Mutex and the built-in sync.Map. These techniques ensure safe concurrent access to maps in multi-threaded environments.
This question was asked to me by Radisys for the role of Golang Developer.
 Approach 1: SafeMap with sync.Mutex This implementation uses sync.Mutex to synchronize access to a map.
Structure and Methods 1. SafeMap Struct Contains:
 mu sync.Mutex: The lock to synchronize map access.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
