<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HowTo on programmerCave</title>
    <link>https://programmercave.com/tags/HowTo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HowTo on programmerCave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://programmercave.com/tags/HowTo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Resize Partitions in Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/How-to-Resize-Partitions-in-Arch-Linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/How-to-Resize-Partitions-in-Arch-Linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Running out of space on your root partition can be a frustrating experience when using Arch Linux. Fortunately, resizing your partitions can be done easily with the help of a live USB or CD and the GParted partition editor. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the steps to resize your partitions and increase the size of your root partition in Arch Linux.&#xA;Step 1: Boot into a Live USB or CD</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complete Guide: Installing, Setting Up, and Removing PostgreSQL in Linux</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/Complete-Guide-Installing-Setting-Up-and-Removing-PostgreSQL-in-Linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/Complete-Guide-Installing-Setting-Up-and-Removing-PostgreSQL-in-Linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction PostgreSQL is an open-source relational database management system. It is known for its reliability, scalability, and extensibility, making it a popular choice for enterprise-level applications. In this tutorial, we will cover how to install and set up PostgreSQL in Linux, how to create a database and table, how to insert values into the table, how to log in to a user and database, and how to completely remove PostgreSQL including all related files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to scroll Amazon Affiliate Marketing cards horizontally on a website</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/How-to-scroll-Amazon-Affiliate-Marketing-cards-horizontally-on-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/How-to-scroll-Amazon-Affiliate-Marketing-cards-horizontally-on-a-website/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to put my amazon affiliate marketing product on website. But on smaller screens it was messing up my website&amp;rsquo;s interface. I searched on internet tried many things but no result. Then I tried it with &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; in html and css and it worked. Here is the code for that.&#xA;Table with only one reow is needed and we will put products&amp;rsquo; card on that row and when the table width is greater than screen&amp;rsquo;s width it will scroll horizontaly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create Password list using CUPP tool on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/How-to-create-Password-list-using-CUPP-tool-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/How-to-create-Password-list-using-CUPP-tool-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>People do not create complex passwords. Their password consists of their name or surname, date of birth, favourite football team etc, so they can remember it easily. There are many tools which create password list using these parameters. Here we are going to discuss about one such tool CUPP and how to create password lists using it.&#xA;CUPP(Common User Passwords Profiler) is python based free and open source tool which generates wordlist for a specific user based on the information provided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install graphics.h C/C&#43;&#43; library on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://programmercave.com/How-to-Install-graphics.h-C-C-library-on-Ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://programmercave.com/How-to-Install-graphics.h-C-C-library-on-Ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>In this post we are going to install graphics.h library on Ubuntu and to use it with gcc or g++ compiler. graphics.h provides access to a simple graphics library that makes it possible to draw lines, rectangles, ovals, arcs, polygons, images, and strings on a graphical window. To know about functions in graphic.h library in C/C++ visit here.&#xA;To use graphics.hon Ubuntu platform we need to compile and install libgraph. libgraph is an implementation of the TurboC graphics API (graphics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
